Guide to the Claudia Horwitz Papers, 1988-2013 RL.10137
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Claudia Horwitz papers
1988-2013
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Sallie Bingham Center for Women's History and Culture
Horwitz, Claudia
RL.10137
8.5 Linear Feet 14 boxes
Collection contains personal and professional papers of Claudia Horwitz, a Chapel Hill spiritual activist, author, and founder of Stone Circles.
Provenance
The Claudia Horwitz papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in November, 2013.
Collection Overview
Collection includes, but is not limited to writings, research and subject files, project files, talks/speeches, and files documenting group work.
Biographical note
Claudia Horwitz founded the spiritual activism organization Stone Circles in 1995 and led the organization until 2013. Her previous work includes developing youth leadership, supporting struggles for economic justice, and strengthening social change organizations. She was a Rockefeller Foundation Next Generation Leadership Fellow and has a masters' degree in public policy from Duke University. She is the author of The Spiritual Activist: Practices to Transform Your Life, Your Work, and Your World (PenguinCompass, 2002), and serves on the board of the Seasons Fund for Social Transformation.
Arrangement
Collection is arranged in the same chronological order in which it was received, with a grouping of research and writing drafts at the end.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48-hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Youth -- Political activity; Womens' history -- North Carolina; Spirituality -- Women; Social change -- United States; Economic justice -- United States; Stone Circles; Sallie Bingham Center for Women's History and Culture; Horwitz, Claudia
- 1988-1996, 1 boxes
  - Community reserve center, 1 folders (Box 1)
  - NSCAHH, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Empty the Shelter planning, 1 folders (Box 1)
  - Up and Out of Poverty, 1 folders (Box 1)
  - Olympics, 1 folders (Box 1)
  - Empty the Shelter - Oakland, 1 folders (Box 1)
- 1988-1999, 1 boxes
  - Empty the Shelter - National, 1 folders (Box 2)
  - Empty the Shelter - Philadelphia, 1 folders (Box 2)
  - Empty the Shelter - Reunion, 1 folders (Box 2)
  - Empty the Shelter - database, 1 folders (Box 2)
  - Summer of Service, 1993; 1 folders (Box 2)
  - Conference program and notes, 1993; 1 folders (Box 2)
  - Who Cares?, 1993; 1 folders (Box 2)
  - Echoing Green pamphlets, 1 folders (Box 2)
  - Echoing Green application and correspondence, 1 folders
  - Echoing Green Fellowship Application, 1 folders (Box 2)
  - Fellows Conferences, 1 folders (Box 2)
  - Public Service Application, 1994; 1 folders (Box 2)
  - Echoing Green transition, 1997-1999; 1 folders (Box 2)
- 1998-1997, 2 boxes
  - Fellows, 1 folders (Box 3)
  - CYC closeout, 1 folders (Box 3)
  - CYC thesis, 1 folders (Box 3)
  - CYC archives, 1 folders (Box 3)
  - Public Allies, 1 folders (Box 3)
  - Media AAS, 1 folders (Box 3)
  - Raising children to become caring contributors, 1 folders (Box 3)
  - Seeds, 1 folders (Box 3)
  - NC Commission, 1995; 1 folders (Box 3)
  - Interfaith Alliance, 1996; 1 folders (Box 3)
  - SRDI general, 1997; 1 folders (Box 3)
  - NC Fund with treatment, 1 folders (Box 4)
  - NC Fund agenda, 1 folders (Box 4)
  - NC Fund steering committee, 1 folders (Box 4)
  - NC Fund grant, 1 folders (Box 4)
  - NC Fund general, 1 folders (Box 4)
  - NC Fund current working group, 1 folders (Box 4)
  - NC Fund conference, 1 folders (Box 4)
  - NC Fund the next wave, 1 folders (Box 4)
  - Southern Community Partners, 1 folders (Box 4)
  - Southern Community Partners retreat, 1996-1997; 1 folders (Box 4)
- 1997-2005, 4 boxes
  - Notes, 1 folders (Box 5)
  - Notes, EPU, 1998; 1 folders (Box 5)
  - Building Community and Capacity, 1 folders (Box 5)
  - EPU staff orientation, 1 folders (Box 5)
  - EPU planning, 1997-1999; 3 folders (Box 5)
  - EPU Mentor Handbook, 1998; 1 folders (Box 5)
  - Mentors/Lining, 1 folders (Box 5)
  - EPU Program, 1 folders (Box 5)
  - COV groups, 1 folders (Box 5)
  - Academic track, 1 folders (Box 6)
  - Community life - ideas, plans, 1 folders (Box 6)
  - EPU yearbooks, 1997-1999; 1 folders (Box 6)
  - EPU artwork, 1998; 1 folders (Box 6)
  - EPU junkies, 1 folders (Box 6)
  - Evaluations, 1 folders (Box 6)
  - EPU Community Life paper, 1 folders (Box 6)
  - EPU, 2000-2001; 2 folders (Box 6)
  - Lisa Sullivan and Listen, 1998; 1 folders (Box 6)
  - Grace, 1999 (Box 6)
  - Parliament World's Religions, 1999; 1 folders (Box 6)
  - WCR, 1 folders (Box 6)
  - TRC, 1 folders (Box 6)
  - History of the Black Housewives League of South Africa and Lesotho, 1 folders (Box 6)
  - Circle of Sacred Silence, 1 folders (Box 7)
  - Solidarity Conference Ctr., 1 folders (Box 7)
  - Candles of Hope, 1999-2001; 1 folders (Box 7)
  - September 11, 2001 services and memorials, 1 folders (Box 4)
  - CFG, 1 folders (Box 6)
  - CFG gathering, 2001; 1 folders (Box 7)
  - Interfaith Service Caps, 2002; 1 folders (Box 7)
  - Balkans training for trainers, 2001; 1 folders (Box 7)
  - Romania, 2002; 1 folders (Box 7)
  - Balkan Summer Institute Vukerar, 1 folders (Box 7)
  - Iraq aides commentary, 1 folders (Box 8)
  - Rockefeller application and interview, 1 folders (Box 8)
  - Rockefeller mailing info, 1 folders (Box 8)
  - Rockefeller module one, 1 folders (Box 7)
  - NGL evolution, 2003; 1 folders (Box 8)
  - NGL NC module for module 5, 1 folders (Box 8)
  - NGL 3.0, 2006; 1 folders (Box 8)
  - NGL evals, 1 folders (Box 8)
  - NGL selection overview design, 1 folders (Box 8)
- 2005-2013, 3 boxes
  - TFC training, 1 folders (Box 9)
  - TFC homecoming, 1 folders (Box 9)
  - TFC miscellaneous, 1 folders (Box 9)
  - TFC budget info, 1 folders (Box 9)
  - TFC, 2004-2005; 1 folders (Box 9)
  - Wellesley, 2005; 1 folders (Box 9)
  - Funding circles: logistics, invites, etc., 1 folders (Box 9)
  - Seasons Fund meeting agenda, 1 folders (Box 9)
  - Rabbi retreat, 2009; 1 folders (Box 9)
  - East, 1 folders (Box 9)
  - Garrison Institute meeting, 2012; 1 folders (Box 9)
  - Early vision documents - place, 1 folders (Box 10)
  - Class presentations, 1 folders (Box 10)
  - Correspondence, 1 folders (Box 10)
  - Spirit of Generation X, 1 folders (Box 10)
  - National Service memo, 1 folders (Box 10)
  - South Africa, 2 folders (Box 10)
  - Education as Transformation article, 1 folders (Box 10)
  - Community TOBs article, 1 folders (Box 10)
  - Stone's Throw outline, 1 folders (Box 10)
  - Writings, 1 folders (Box 10)
  - Book cover and title, 1 folders (Box 10)
  - Book - Viking correspondence, 1 folders (Box 10)
  - Book in progress, 1 folders (Box 10)
  - Publishing, 1 folders (Box 11)
  - New Society Publishers, 1 folders (Box 11)
  - Graphics, 2 folders (Box 11)
  - ISBN, 1 folders (Box 11)
  - Copyright info/LCCN, 1 folders (Box 11)
  - Book design, 1 folders (Box 11)
  - Book outline, 1 folders (Box 11)
  - Book responses, notes, etc., 1 folders (Box 11)
  - Amy Rennert and Stu H., 1 folders (Box 11)
  - Edits from people, 1 folders (Box 11)
  - Photos/contact sheets, 1 folders (Box 11)
  - Book readings, 2002-2003; 1 folders (Box 11)
- Research/Drafts, 3 boxes
  - Building sustainable communities, 1 folders (Box 11)
  - Agenda: coordinators meeting, 1993; 1 folders (Box 11)
  - Book revisions, 2 folders (Box 11)
  - Stone's Throw drafts, 3 folders (Box 11)
  - Silence, 1 folders (Box 11)
  - Meditation, 1 folders (Box 11)
  - Prayer, 1 folders (Box 13)
  - Spiritual practice, 1 folders (Box 13)
  - Inspiration, 1 folders (Box 13)
  - Ritual, 1 folders (Box 13)
  - Words and stories, 1 folders (Box 13)
  - Art, 1 folders (Box 13)
  - Arts programs, 1 folders (Box 13)
  - Elements/nature, 1 folders (Box 13)
  - Paganism/witchcraft, 1 folders (Box 13)
  - Relationships, 1 folders (Box 13)
  - Movement, 2 folders (Box 13-14)
  - Healing, 1 folders (Box 14)
  - Stone Circles, 1 folders (Box 14)
  - Food, culture, spirituality, 1 folders (Box 14)
  - Celebrations, 1 folders (Box 14)
  - Space, 2 folders (Box 14)
  - Resources, 1 folders (Box 14)
  - Work/justice, 1 folders (Box 14)
  - Religion and social justice, 1 folders (Box 14)
  - General spiritual stuff, 1 folders (Box 14)
  - Religion, 1 folders (Box 14)